# NIKHII GUNTI

1315, W.3rd Ave, A3, Stillwater, OK

□ 405-762-0337 | ■ nikhil.gunti@okstate.edu | • nikhilgunti | • gunti-nikhil/

### **Professional Summary**

Business acumen with 2+ years of experience in product development domain having hands-on SQL, Python, R, and other technologies. Strong working knowledge performing data analysis & building models using Pandas, Numpy, Scikit and developing Tableau dashboards.

#### Education

#### Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK

CGPA: 4.0

MASTERS IN BUSINESS ANALYTICS & DATA SCIENCE

Aug. 2019 - May. 2021

JNTUH College of Engineering, Hyderabad, India

CGPA: 3.5

B.Tech in Flectronics and Communication Engineering

Aug. 2013 - May. 2017

### Technical Skills & Certifications

- Programming Languages: C/C++, SAS, SQL, R, Python, Matlab, Verilog
- Tools: R Studio, Tableau, JMP, Power BI, Postgre SQL, Visual Studio, Frameworks: Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch
- · Certifications: Computer Vision Nanodegree- Udacity, Deep Learning Specialization Coursera, SAS Programming Certified Specialist - SAS®, 'Become a Data Scientist' - LinkedIn course, 'Innovation and Information Technology Management' by IIMB

## Work Experience

**Concat Systems** Dallas, TX

DATA SCIENCE INTERN May. 2020 - Present

- · Working on AI solutions for several car rental agencies Object detection and tracking on cars demo videos
- Implemented various object detection algorithms and trying to integrate DeepSORT algorithm to detect 20 custom objects in a video

#### **Spears School of Business - OSU**

Stillwater, OK

**GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT** 

Jan. 2020 - May. 2020

 Assisted Dr. Jihoon Jhang for the course 'MKTG 3323-Consumer and Market Behavior' and Dr. Ritchie Liu for the course 'MKTG 4683-Managerial Strategic Marketing' with classroom instructions, exams, grading, record keeping, and research papers

**Wipro Limited** Hyderabad, India

PRODUCT ENGINEER

Aug. 2017 - Jul. 2019

- Data Analytics Ran Naive Bayes & logistic regression models for multi-class text classification based on case description. Also, analyzed the factors behind lease cases and tried to predict the number of lease issues for next quarter.
- Lease Accounting Consulting Interacted with clients all over the world and assisted them with both functional & technical issues of the product IBM TRIRIGA, specifically real estate module of the product
- Case Resolution Debugged platform & application issues of product and resolved 234 client cases in a year (2nd in team of 19)
- Content Creation Created and developed training content of 8.5 hours for Lease Accounting module of the TRIRIGA product from the scratch solitary, which is being consumed by most of the Fortune 500 companies and their clients
- Team Management Promoted to team lead and entrusted with responsibility to manage a team of 3 experienced professionals

# Academic Projects

# **Deep Learning and Computer Vision**

OSU

RESEARCH STUDENT - INDEPENDENT STUDY

Apr. 2020 - present

- Working on research paper "Improving Object Detection with Commonsense Reasoning" for CVPR-2020
- Trained Yolo, Faster-RCNN, Detectron 2 on custom data using Tensorflow & PyTorch frameworks and built custom code for evaluation metrics like Top-5 accuracy, AP for each class, confusion matrix based on GT BB's
- · Submitted research paper 'Skin Cancer detection using Deep Learning techniques' to Western region SAS conference-2020

**MetroTech Center Retention** OSU

DATA ANALYST Aug. 2019 - Nov. 2019

- · Analyzed past 5 years of student survey responses to improve satisfaction rate. Interesting correlations between the variables influencing retention rate were drawn for further analysis
- · Built Multinomial logistic regression model to identify significant factors and created interactive visualization dashboards

#### **Customer Feedback Analysis of Apple Products**

OSU

· Scraped data from Twitter & other social media websites and performed web content mining to analyze user's feedback on recently launched Apple iPhones. Used libraries like NLTK, Gensim to perform sentiment analysis & named entity of customer reviews

# Leadership & Management Roles.

- President: My role as President for Business Analytics Student Association (BASA) includes organizing technical workshops by industry leaders, meetups/fun-activities, connecting BASA members with alumni network
- Community Development Volunteer: Worked with 'YouthForSeva' to stabilize the financial status of impoverished kids in public schools by enabling them to bag scholarships and conducted career empowerment sessions & weekend classes on maths and science

NIKHII GUNTI · RÉSUMÉ JUNE 13, 2020 1